<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Mapping for the SDGs on Open Mapping for SDGs</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Open Mapping for the SDGs on Open Mapping for SDGs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Goal 1 - No Poverty</title>
      <link>/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/sdg-goal-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/sdg-goal-01/</guid>
      <description>End poverty in all its forms everywhere “Extreme poverty rates have fallen by more than half since 1990. While this is a remarkable achievement, one-in-five people in developing regions still live on less than $1.90 a day. Millions more make little more than this daily amount and are at risk of slipping back into extreme poverty.”
Poverty elimination projects to map low income (often slum) areas can support humanitarian and development programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kihumbe- Survey Digitization and Mapping for HIV Monitoring</title>
      <link>/pages/part-iii-case-studies-in-integration-and-implementation/1._kihumbe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/part-iii-case-studies-in-integration-and-implementation/1._kihumbe/</guid>
      <description>Kihumbe NGO (Mbeya, Tanzania) The Challenge KIHUMBE, a non-profit NGO based in the southern highlights of Tanzania, provides HIV-related services and counselling to at-risk individuals from vulnerable populations. Prior to HOT’s intervention, KIHUMBE used local paper-based methods to conduct data collection and generate daily reports of people receiving services. Data availability and data access was a common challenge for staff. Peer educators—a group of KIHUMBE volunteers who conduct citizen outreach in areas with high HIV prevalence—needed updated data showing where “hotspots” (areas like motels or nightclubs where HIV is at higher risk of transmission) are in a given neighbourhood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goal 2 - Zero Hunger</title>
      <link>/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/sdg-goal-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/sdg-goal-02/</guid>
      <description>End hunger, achieve food security and improved nutrition and promote sustainable agriculture “Our soils, freshwater, oceans, forests and biodiversity are being rapidly degraded. Climate change is putting even more pressure on the resources we depend on, increasing risks associated with disasters such as droughts and floods. Many rural women and men can no longer make ends meet on their land, forcing them to migrate to cities in search of opportunities.”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UBOS- Open Mapping Integration to Improve the National Census</title>
      <link>/pages/part-iii-case-studies-in-integration-and-implementation/2._ubos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/part-iii-case-studies-in-integration-and-implementation/2._ubos/</guid>
      <description>Uganda Bureau of Statistics (UBOS) (Kampala, Uganda) The Challenge The Uganda Bureau of Statistics (UBOS) is the government agency mandated to collect and maintain baseline data across the nation. Its work is guided by various government stakeholders and then shared more broadly for analysis, program design and service delivery in communities. Prior to HOT’s intervention, data collectors at UBOS would trek through counties and villages across the country with bundles of paper maps and GPS devices, inputting information by pen onto printed sheets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goal 3 - Good Health and Wellbeing</title>
      <link>/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/sdg-goal-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/sdg-goal-03/</guid>
      <description>Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages “Significant strides have been made in increasing life expectancy and reducing some of the common killers responsible for child and maternal mortality. Major progress has also been made on increasing access to clean water and sanitation, reducing malaria, tuberculosis, polio and the spread of HIV/AIDS. However, many more efforts are needed to control a wide range of diseases and address many different persistent and emerging health issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goal 4 - Quality Education</title>
      <link>/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/sdg-goal-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/sdg-goal-04/</guid>
      <description>Ensure inclusive and quality education for all and promote lifelong learning “Basic literacy skills across the world have improved tremendously, yet bolder efforts are needed to achieve universal education goals for all. For example, the world has achieved equality in primary education between girls and boys, but few countries have achieved that target at all levels of education.”
Open mapping provides a two-fold benefit towards reaching the SDG for education: assisting partners, governments, and local communities understand gaps in services and distribution of educational facilities, as well as providing an opportunity for individuals in these groups to gain technical and vocational skills such as GIS and surveying.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goal 5 - Gender Equality</title>
      <link>/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/sdg-goal-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/sdg-goal-05/</guid>
      <description>Achieve gender equality and empower all women and girls “Gender equality is not only a fundamental human right, but a necessary foundation for a peaceful, prosperous and sustainable world. Providing women and girls with equal access to education, health care, decent work, and representation in political and economic decision-making processes will fuel sustainable economies and benefit societies and humanity at large.”
Open mapping projects can support gender equality by creating data about gendered problems that affect women and girls, and working to prioritize the involvement of all members of society in decision-making processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goal 6 - Clean Water and Sanitation</title>
      <link>/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/sdg-goal-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/sdg-goal-06/</guid>
      <description>Ensure access to water and sanitation for all “Clean, accessible water for all is an essential part of the world we want to live in and there is sufficient fresh water on the planet to achieve this. However, due to bad economics or poor infrastructure, millions of people including children die every year from diseases associated with inadequate water supply, sanitation and hygiene. Water scarcity, poor water quality and inadequate sanitation negatively impact food security, livelihood choices and educational opportunities for poor families across the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goal 7 - Affordable and Clean Energy</title>
      <link>/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/sdg-goal-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/sdg-goal-07/</guid>
      <description>Ensure access to affordable, reliable, sustainable and modern energy for all “Energy is central to nearly every major challenge and opportunity the world faces today. Be it for jobs, security, climate change, food production or increasing incomes, access to energy for all is essential. Transitioning the global economy towards clean and sustainable sources of energy is one of our greatest challenges in the coming decades. Sustainable energy is an opportunity – it transforms lives, economies and the planet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goal 8 - Decent Work and Economic Growth</title>
      <link>/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/sdg-goal-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/sdg-goal-08/</guid>
      <description>Promote inclusive and sustainable economic growth, employment and decent work for all “Roughly half the world’s population still lives on the equivalent of about US$2 a day. And in too many places, having a job doesn’t guarantee the ability to escape from poverty. This slow and uneven progress requires us to rethink and retool our economic and social policies aimed at eradicating poverty.”
By incorporating youth and other vulnerable populations, open mapping activities can provide vocational training in the latest open source GIS tools to substantially reduce the proportion of youth not in employment, education, or training and help achieve full and productive employment and decent work for all women and men, including for young people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goal 9 - Industry, Innovation, and Infrastructure</title>
      <link>/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/sdg-goal-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/sdg-goal-09/</guid>
      <description>Build resilient infrastructure, promote inclusive and sustainable industrialization and foster innovation &amp;ldquo;Investments in infrastructure – transport, irrigation, energy and information and communication technology – are crucial to achieving sustainable development and empowering communities in many countries. It has long been recognized that growth in productivity and incomes, and improvements in health and education outcomes require investment in infrastructure.&amp;quot;
Mapping basic infrastructure such as roads and buildings is often the first step in understanding and solving larger issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goal 11 - Sustainable Cities and Communities</title>
      <link>/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/sdg-goal-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/sdg-goal-11/</guid>
      <description>Goal 11: Make cities inclusive, safe, resilient and sustainable “The challenges cities face can be overcome in ways that allow them to continue to thrive and grow, while improving resource use and reducing pollution and poverty. The future we want includes cities of opportunities for all, with access to basic services, energy, housing, transportation and more.”
In line with the New Urban Agenda and the Kuala Lumpur Declaration, open mapping can be used as a tool to improve equity, resilience, and quality of life for urban residents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goal 12 - Responsible Consumption and Production</title>
      <link>/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/sdg-goal-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/sdg-goal-12/</guid>
      <description>Ensure sustainable consumption and production patterns Sustainable consumption and production is about promoting resource and energy efficiency, sustainable infrastructure, and providing access to basic services, green and decent jobs and a better quality of life for all. Its implementation helps to achieve overall development plans, reduce future economic, environmental and social costs, strengthen economic competitiveness and reduce poverty.
Approaching solid waste and consumption geospatially can help urban planners and governments understand distribution and patterns of waste and production issues their city faces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goal 13 - Climate Action</title>
      <link>/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/sdg-goal-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/sdg-goal-13/</guid>
      <description>Goal 13: Take urgent action to combat climate change and its impacts Climate change is now affecting every country on every continent. It is disrupting national economies and affecting lives, costing people, communities and countries dearly today and even more tomorrow. Weather patterns are changing, sea levels are rising, weather events are becoming more extreme and greenhouse gas emissions are now at their highest levels in history. Without action, the world’s average surface temperature is likely to surpass 3 degrees centigrade this century.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goal 14 - Life Below Water</title>
      <link>/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/sdg-goal-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/sdg-goal-14/</guid>
      <description>Conserve and sustainably use the oceans, seas and marine resources Our oceans — their temperature, circulation, chemistry, and ecosystems — play a fundamental role in making Earth habitable. Our rainwater, drinking water, weather, climate, coastlines, much of our food, and even the oxygen in the air we breathe, are all ultimately provided and regulated by the sea. Throughout history, oceans and seas have been vital conduits for trade and transportation. Careful management of this essential global resource is a key feature of a sustainable future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goal 15 - Life on Land</title>
      <link>/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/sdg-goal-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/sdg-goal-15/</guid>
      <description>Sustainably manage forests, combat desertification, halt and reverse land degradation, halt biodiversity loss “Forests cover 30 percent of the Earth’s surface and in addition to providing food security and shelter, forests are key to combating climate change, protecting biodiversity and the homes of the indigenous population. Thirteen million hectares of forests are being lost every year while the persistent degradation of drylands has led to the desertification of 3.6 billion hectares.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goal 16 - Peace, Justice, and Strong Institutions</title>
      <link>/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/sdg-goal-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/sdg-goal-16/</guid>
      <description>Goal 16: Promote just, peaceful and inclusive societies _“The threats of international homicide, violence against children, human trafficking and sexual violence are important to address to promote peaceful and inclusive societies for sustainable development. They pave the way for the provision of access to justice for all and for building effective, accountable institutions at all levels. _
To tackle these challenges and build a more peaceful, inclusive societies, there needs to be more efficient and transparent regulations put in place and comprehensive, realistic government budgets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goal 17 - Partnerships</title>
      <link>/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/sdg-goal-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/sdg-goal-17/</guid>
      <description>Revitalize the global partnership for sustainable development &amp;ldquo;A successful sustainable development agenda requires partnerships between governments, the private sector and civil society. These inclusive partnerships built upon principles and values, a shared vision, and shared goals that place people and the planet at the centre, are needed at the global, regional, national and local level.&amp;quot;
The active participation in Communities of Practice (CoP), including particularily governments, private sector and civil society strenghens partnerships for equal development and diverse approach for creative solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1. Setting the Stage for Program Sustainability</title>
      <link>/pages/part-ii-integrating-and-implementing-open-mapping-efforts/1.-setting-the-stage-for-program-sustainability/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/part-ii-integrating-and-implementing-open-mapping-efforts/1.-setting-the-stage-for-program-sustainability/</guid>
      <description>Maps have the power to tell stories about people and places and the ability to show patterns of ideas or issues through space and time. Citizen-generated data can leverage the local knowledge and expertise of individuals living in these communities to participate in addressing and identifying the societal issues being faced. Combining the power of maps and the value of community-led data collection enables a new way of understanding a group of people that a traditional approach to surveying, for example, may be unable to capture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2. Integrating workflow into existing projects</title>
      <link>/pages/part-ii-integrating-and-implementing-open-mapping-efforts/2.-integrating-workflow-into-existing-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/part-ii-integrating-and-implementing-open-mapping-efforts/2.-integrating-workflow-into-existing-projects/</guid>
      <description>Many organizations want to incorporate open mapping into their operations but don’t know where to start, believe that it requires rebuilding workflows from scratch, or that their operations will not be able to integrate open mapping. However, the open mapping workflow can be, and should be, integrated into existing workflows. The first step towards using open mapping is analyzing how existing projects and workflows can be altered and improved with integration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3. Designing an Open Mapping Project</title>
      <link>/pages/part-ii-integrating-and-implementing-open-mapping-efforts/3.-designing-an-open-mapping-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/part-ii-integrating-and-implementing-open-mapping-efforts/3.-designing-an-open-mapping-project/</guid>
      <description>Designing and implementing an open mapping project can be complex, especially if there are ambitious mapping goals or a large group of partners involved. Several resources exist that provide further detail on navigating the mapping process:
 Open Cities Project Guide - the World Bank Global Facility for Disaster Reduction and Recovery (GFDRR) and Humanitarian OpenStreetMap Team (HOT) published a guide that can be downloaded at http://www.opencitiesproject.org/guide/. Participatory Mapping Toolkit - Humanitarian OpenStreetMap Team (HOT) published a guide for open mapping projects in the context of refugees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4. Data Creation &amp; Collection - Quick Start Guide</title>
      <link>/pages/part-ii-integrating-and-implementing-open-mapping-efforts/4.-data-creation-and-collection-quick-start-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/part-ii-integrating-and-implementing-open-mapping-efforts/4.-data-creation-and-collection-quick-start-guide/</guid>
      <description>Creating data for OpenStreetMap typically takes two forms: remote mapping and field data collection. Remote mapping is the process of tracing infrastructure such as buildings and roads into OpenStreetMap using aerial or satellite imagery. This process allows for volunteers and team members to create basemaps anywhere in the world with only a computer and internet connection.
Collecting data on the ground is an integral part of editing OSM. This data is typically richer in detail and more accurate than map data that is generated solely by remote tracing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5. Quality control/assurance</title>
      <link>/pages/part-ii-integrating-and-implementing-open-mapping-efforts/5.-quality-control-and-assurance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/part-ii-integrating-and-implementing-open-mapping-efforts/5.-quality-control-and-assurance/</guid>
      <description>Quality Assurance and Quality Control is the process by which mappers, and OpenStreetMap contributors in general, check data to ensure that all information uploaded to OSM meets high standards for usage and to prevent vandalism. As OpenStreetMap is a free and open platform that anyone can use and edit, it is critical to the sustainability of open data and OSM that everyone participates in the quality assurance and quality control process – from field data collection to data cleaning to long-term maintenance of existing OSM data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6. Using Open Data &amp; Maps for Analysis, Display and Decision-Making</title>
      <link>/pages/part-ii-integrating-and-implementing-open-mapping-efforts/6.-using-open-data-and-maps-for-analysis-display-and-decision-making/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/part-ii-integrating-and-implementing-open-mapping-efforts/6.-using-open-data-and-maps-for-analysis-display-and-decision-making/</guid>
      <description>There are a handful of free tools available to extract and utilize OSM data for decision-making. By either using OSM data in conjunction with free population data sets from, for example, World Pop or other thematic datasets from the Humanitarian Data Exchange or even combining it with your own generated data, various tools can be used to clean, analyze and visualize information to inform project planning and decision-making.
  uMap lets you create maps with OSM layers quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>