<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Part III - Case Studies in Integration and Implementation on Open Mapping for SDGs</title>
    <link>/pages/part-iii-case-studies-in-integration-and-implementation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Part III - Case Studies in Integration and Implementation on Open Mapping for SDGs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/pages/part-iii-case-studies-in-integration-and-implementation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Kihumbe- Survey Digitization and Mapping for HIV Monitoring</title>
      <link>/pages/part-iii-case-studies-in-integration-and-implementation/1._kihumbe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/part-iii-case-studies-in-integration-and-implementation/1._kihumbe/</guid>
      <description>Kihumbe NGO (Mbeya, Tanzania) The Challenge KIHUMBE, a non-profit NGO based in the southern highlights of Tanzania, provides HIV-related services and counselling to at-risk individuals from vulnerable populations. Prior to HOT’s intervention, KIHUMBE used local paper-based methods to conduct data collection and generate daily reports of people receiving services. Data availability and data access was a common challenge for staff. Peer educators—a group of KIHUMBE volunteers who conduct citizen outreach in areas with high HIV prevalence—needed updated data showing where “hotspots” (areas like motels or nightclubs where HIV is at higher risk of transmission) are in a given neighbourhood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UBOS- Open Mapping Integration to Improve the National Census</title>
      <link>/pages/part-iii-case-studies-in-integration-and-implementation/2._ubos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/part-iii-case-studies-in-integration-and-implementation/2._ubos/</guid>
      <description>Uganda Bureau of Statistics (UBOS) (Kampala, Uganda) The Challenge The Uganda Bureau of Statistics (UBOS) is the government agency mandated to collect and maintain baseline data across the nation. Its work is guided by various government stakeholders and then shared more broadly for analysis, program design and service delivery in communities. Prior to HOT’s intervention, data collectors at UBOS would trek through counties and villages across the country with bundles of paper maps and GPS devices, inputting information by pen onto printed sheets.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>