<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Part IV - Using Open Data and Maps to Meet and Monitor SDGs on GPSDD Documentation</title>
    <link>/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Part IV - Using Open Data and Maps to Meet and Monitor SDGs on GPSDD Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/sdg-goal-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/sdg-goal-4/</guid>
      <description>Goal 4: Ensure inclusive and quality education for all and promote lifelong learning “Basic literacy skills across the world have improved tremendously, yet bolder efforts are needed to achieve universal education goals for all. For example, the world has achieved equality in primary education between girls and boys, but few countries have achieved that target at all levels of education.”
Open mapping provides a two-fold benefit towards reaching the SDG for education: assisting partners, governments, and local communities understand gaps in services and distribution of educational facilities, as well as providing an opportunity for individuals in these groups to gain technical and vocational skills such as GIS and surveying.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goal 1</title>
      <link>/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/sdg-goal-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/part-iv-using-open-data-and-maps-to-meet-and-monitor-sdgs/sdg-goal-1/</guid>
      <description>Goal 1: End poverty in all its forms everywhere “Extreme poverty rates have fallen by more than half since 1990. While this is a remarkable achievement, one-in-five people in developing regions still live on less than $1.90 a day. Millions more make little more than this daily amount and are at risk of slipping back into extreme poverty.”
Poverty elimination projects to map low income (often slum) areas can support humanitarian and development programming.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>